<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Cecina Babich Morrow</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Cecina Babich Morrow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Goldwater Highlight</title>
      <link>/post/goldwater-highlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/goldwater-highlight/</guid>
      <description>This is just a quick post to provide a link to the Goldwater Scholar Social Media Highlight that Nina Singh wrote about me. You can find the pdf to the article here. Huge thanks to the Goldwater social media team for including me in this!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copying R libraries to a USB</title>
      <link>/post/2019-06-07-usb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-06-07-usb/</guid>
      <description>From Wild Green Memes for Ecological Fiends.   Inspiration for this post A few people in my lab are headed to a workshop in Colombia next week, and due to the possibility of intermittent wi-fi, they need to load all of the workshop materials onto USB drives. They need R with certain packages on the USBs in versions compatible with both Macs and PCs, so I offered to help out by loading my Mac version of R and my packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting resolution and aspect ratios in R</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-23-highres-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-23-highres-figures/</guid>
      <description>Bizarro.   Inspiration for this post I recently needed to make some figures to present and noticed that the ones I was importing from saved R plots were showing up fuzzy on the presentation. Shortly afterwards, I had interns trying to generate figures with the same aspect ratio from different computers. I did a little digging and found this method for saving figures with specified resolutions and aspect ratios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thresholding species distribution models</title>
      <link>/post/2019-04-12-sdm-threshold/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-04-12-sdm-threshold/</guid>
      <description>From left to right: unmodified species distribution model, minimum training presence threshold, and 10th percentile threshold.   Inspiration for this post Conservation is often the main motivation behind studying where a species lives – having a model of a species’ range can help scientists assess whether it is at risk of extinction, designate protected regions to preserve its habitat, and study potential impacts of human activity. When we create species distribution models using common methods like Maxent, the result is a map of predicted habitat suitability or probability of species presence, such as the one below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting alpha hulls to spatial objects</title>
      <link>/post/2019-03-18-alpha-hull/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-03-18-alpha-hull/</guid>
      <description>Alpha hulls (α = 20) around occurrence points for two species of sloths.   Inspiration for this post In species distribution modeling, one of the key steps requires the researcher to select a “background region” for the species, i.e. a region over which a machine learning model will compare the environment of the “background points” with the environment at points where the species is known to occur.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Meteorites Part 1: Calculating percent weights</title>
      <link>/post/2019-02-20-meteoritecluster1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-02-20-meteoritecluster1/</guid>
      <description>Intensity of iron in a meteorite.   Earlier this month I participated in the American Museum of Natural History’s annual hackathon (see my last post for details about the event overall). During the hackathon, I worked with Katy Abbott, another Helen Fellow at the museum with me, to use a machine learning algorithm called DBSCAN to tackle our challenge. This post explains the process we used to complete the first step of the challenge: estimating the percent weights of elements in a meteorite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python in RMarkdown</title>
      <link>/post/2019-02-20-pythonrmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-02-20-pythonrmd/</guid>
      <description>The reticulate package logo.   Using Python in RMarkdown In order to write blog posts using Python code, I wanted to figure out a way to include Python code chunks in RMarkdowns. When you insert a code chunk in RMarkdown, you have the option of specifying the language of that chunk: the default is R, but you can also insert a Bash, SQL, Python, etc. code chunk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#HackTheSolarSystem</title>
      <link>/post/2019-02-14-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-02-14-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend I had the opportunity to participate in my first ever hackathon: the #HackTheSolarSystem hackathon hosted by the American Museum of Natural History.
What is a hackathon, anyways? This is a question I got asked countless times this last week as I informed my friends and family that I would be at work all weekend (yes, including Friday night, yes, including Saturday night, no, I will not be able to socialize at all).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grafting phylogenies</title>
      <link>/post/2019-01-09-grafting-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-01-09-grafting-trees/</guid>
      <description>Inspiration for this post This post comes from the finishing touches I needed to put on a paper about life history evolution. The paper compares life history traits across the four groups of tetrapods (amphibians, reptiles, mammals, and birds), so when I carried out the nitty gritty phylogenetic analyses, I used four separate phylogenies. When it came time to make a figure to visualize those analyses, however, I ended up with an unwieldy (and unpublishable) 16-panel figure (four phylogenies by four traits).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging in R</title>
      <link>/post/2019-01-03-debugging-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-01-03-debugging-r/</guid>
      <description>PhD comics Jorge Cham (www.phdcomics.com)   Recently I’ve been part of beta testing a new R package. The package allows users to apply different masks to spcies distribution models to create more ecologically realistic range models. The package itself is very cool, but since it hasn’t been released yet, this post will be short on ecology. Instead, I’m going to focus on the process I’ve been using to debug the package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Google Docs to website</title>
      <link>/post/2018-12-12-add-google-doc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-12-12-add-google-doc/</guid>
      <description>Given that the Academic website theme comes with a place to upload talks, I thought I might as well upload the slides for my Senior Honors presentation. Unfortunately, this was a slightly more difficult task than I anticipated. The default format for slides in Hugo appears to be Markdown slides, which is fine, except when your talk was made in Google Slides.
Google Slides to Markdown? My first thought was that there must be some tool to convert a Google slides talk into a Markdown document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordering website components</title>
      <link>/post/2018-12-11-order-items/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-12-11-order-items/</guid>
      <description>As I continue setting up this site, one of the major things irking me was the order of content on the website. For example, I wasn’t loving that the first thing you saw when visiting the site was the giant picture of my face. I wanted to be able to put content at the top of the site and move information like my bio and work experience towards the bottom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating this website</title>
      <link>/post/2018-12-7-create-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-12-7-create-website/</guid>
      <description>Getting started I’ve been contemplating the idea of creating a website for sometime, but my initial (mostly half-hearted) attempts ran into some serious technological glitches. I started out trying to create a GitHub site using Jekyll, since I knew I wanted my website to be hosted via GitHub to keep all of my code in the same place. After about an hour of unsuccessful commits that resulted in a lovely white page with my name on it, I scrapped the whole venture until I heard about the blogdown R package.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>