<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Cecina Babich Morrow</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Cecina Babich Morrow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Google Docs to website</title>
      <link>/post/add-google-doc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/add-google-doc/</guid>
      <description>Given that the Academic website theme comes with a place to upload talks, I thought I might as well upload the slides for my Senior Honors presentation. Unfortunately, this was a slightly more difficult task than I anticipated. The default format for slides in Hugo appears to be Markdown slides, which is fine, except when your talk was made in Google Slides.
Google Slides to Markdown? My first thought was that there must be some tool to convert a Google slides talk into a Markdown document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordering website components</title>
      <link>/post/2018-12-11-order-items/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-12-11-order-items/</guid>
      <description>As I continue setting up this site, one of the major things irking me was the order of content on the website. For example, I wasn’t loving that the first thing you saw when visiting the site was the giant picture of my face. I wanted to be able to put content at the top of the site and move information like my bio and work experience towards the bottom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating this website</title>
      <link>/post/2018-12-7-create-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-12-7-create-website/</guid>
      <description>Getting started I’ve been contemplating the idea of creating a website for sometime, but my initial (mostly half-hearted) attempts ran into some serious technological glitches. I started out trying to create a GitHub site using Jekyll, since I knew I wanted my website to be hosted via GitHub to keep all of my code in the same place. After about an hour of unsuccessful commits that resulted in a lovely white page with my name on it, I scrapped the whole venture until I heard about the blogdown R package.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>