<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>species distribution modeling on Cecina Babich Morrow</title>
    <link>/categories/species-distribution-modeling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in species distribution modeling on Cecina Babich Morrow</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/species-distribution-modeling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Thresholding species distribution models</title>
      <link>/post/2019-04-12-sdm-threshold/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-04-12-sdm-threshold/</guid>
      <description>Alpha hulls (α = 20) around occurrence points for two species of sloths.   Inspiration for this post Conservation is often the main motivation behind studying where a species lives – having a model of a species’ range can help scientists assess whether it is at risk of extinction, designate protected regions to preserve its habitat, and study potential impacts of human activity. When we create species distribution models using common methods like Maxent, the result is a map of predicted habitat suitability or probability of species presence, such as the one below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting alpha hulls to spatial objects</title>
      <link>/post/2019-03-18-alpha-hull/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-03-18-alpha-hull/</guid>
      <description>Alpha hulls (α = 20) around occurrence points for two species of sloths.   Inspiration for this post In species distribution modeling, one of the key steps requires the researcher to select a “background region” for the species, i.e. a region over which a machine learning model will compare the environment of the “background points” with the environment at points where the species is known to occur.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>